VAISHAKH MENON

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SKILLS SUMMARY

- ●●●● C++, LINUX, C#, Java
- ●●●● Low Latency Application's
- •••• MySQL, Maria DB
- •••• Project Management
- •••• Staff and User Training
- • • Process Improvement

AWARDS RECEIVED

Outstanding leadership Capmatrix Tech (2018)

CONTACT ME AT

- Office Address: 112 Damji Shamji Industrial Estate, LBS Road Vikhroli West. 400079
- vaishakh_hm@yahoo.in
- vaishakhhm@gmail.com
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/vaishakhhm

PROFILE

I am a Software Developer with 8+ years of experience primarily in designing, development, analysis, testing and implementation of various High Frequency Trading (HFT) low latency financial market applications in Linux (C++) and Windows (C#)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Software Developer

Capmatrix Technologies | Aug 2013 - present

- Developed Multiple Exchange (MCX, NSE, BSE, DGCX) connectivity interfaces for in-house trading system.
- Developed and implemented various algorithmic strategies with competitively lowest latency in the futures and options segment of stock market.
- Solely developed and implemented entire futures and options trading Risk Management System.
- Coordinated with clients in installation of software systems and collaborated on the design and implementation of new features.

Software Engineer

Applied Electroptics and Instruments | May 2011 - Jun 2013

- Completed assignments in Instrumentation and embedded systems.
- Assisted in creating Furnace Controller named Oxy-G for the complete combustion of oxygen in the furnace.
- Knowledge in designing control circuit for heavy machinery using PLC's and VVVF Drives.
- Developed Custom Android Applications which were not Android Market oriented

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Bachelors in Information Tech | 2019 - present (Final Year) Mumbai University

Diploma in Computer Engineering | Jun 2009 - May 2012Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education

INTERESTS

- To get a doctorate degree in my profession especially in Quantum Computing
- Creating 2D and 3D games as well as playing them.
- Reading Science Fiction Books